Guide to Adelphi University Catalogs, etc. Cubb.00009
Cubberley Education Library
Adelphi University (formerly: Adelphi College; formerly: Adelphi Academy)
1886-1972
Cubberley Education Library
Cubb.00009
107 item(s)
New York (State)
- Adelphi Academy, 1886-1907; 6 item(s) Catalogs for 1886/87, 1893/94-1894/95, 1904-1907; Located in Brooklyn, New York. Founded 1863 as a school for boys. Girls added in 1867. Adelphi College was chartered in 1896 and Adelphi Academy was under its control.
- Adelphi College, 1903-1964; 45 item(s) Catalogs for 1903/04-1904/05, 1907-1910, 1912-1914, 1916/17-1947/49, 1950/51, 1952/53, 1955/56, 1957/58-1958/59, 1960/62, 1963/64; Located first in Brooklyn, N. Y.; moved to Garden City, N.Y. in 1929. Incorporated by the New York State Regents in 1896.
  - Adelphi Bulletin: Information concerning the Art School and the Normal School for Kindergartners and Art Teachers, 1908; 1 item(s)
  - Adelphi College Division of Graduate Studies, 1950-1963; 10 item(s) 1950/51, 1952/53-1962/63
  - Adelphi College School of Social Work, 1950-1964; 6 item(s) Announcements for 1950/51-1955/56, 1963/64; Located in Garden City, N.Y. A two-year professional curriculum established in 1949.
  - Adelphi College Everning Session, 1961-1963; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1961/62-1962/63
- Adelphi University, 1963-1971; 6 item(s) 1963/64-1965/66, 1967/68-1968/69, 1970/71; Located in Garden City, N.Y. Granted university status in 1963 by the N.Y. State Board of Regents.
  - Adelphi University Graduate School of Arts and Sciences (formerly Division of Graduate Studies), 1963-1972; 9 item(s) Catalogs for 1963/641971/72; Located in Garden City, N.Y.
  - Adelphi University School of Nursing, 1964-1971; 5 item(s) 1964/65, 1966/67-1968/69, 1970/71; Located in Garden City, N.Y.
  - Adelphi University Summer Session, 1965-1968; 3 item(s) Catalogs for 1965, 1967-1968; Located in Garden City, N.Y.
  - Adelphi University School of Business Administration, 1965-1972; 5 item(s) Catalog for 1965/66, 1967/68-1968/69, 1970/71-1971/72
  - Adelphi University School of Social Work, 1965-1969; 4 item(s) Catalogs for 1965/66-1968/69
  - Adelphi University Graduate Program in Special Education, [1965]; 1 item(s) brochure received in 1965.
  - Adelphi Suffolk College (later Dowling College), 1964-1965; 1 item(s) 1964/65; A branch of Adelphi University located in Oakdale, Long Island, N.Y. In 1968 separated to become Dowling College.